This is Beth.
Beth had another bad sleep last night and has woken up feeling tired.
Her curtains are shut and her room is dimly lit.
Some days,
even small tasks feel impossible.
Beth has a lot of tasks to do today,
and she feels very overwhelmed.
She doesn't know where to begin.
The tasks have all blurred together into one huge task.
Beth decides to write down the list of items,
color coding them depending on how long they will take to complete.
Breaking down the tasks by time makes them feel more manageable.
Beth starts off with the shorter tasks first,
watering her plants and then sending a couple of emails.
Starting with short tasks,
first helps to build momentum and encourages Beth
to continue working through her to do list.
Beth makes sure to tidy her room before then
creating the poster design for her work project.
Once this is done,
she can start working on her assignment.
Beth has reached the end of the day.
She still has her assignment to finish,
but the important thing is that progress has been made today.
Beth feels lighter,
proud of herself for making a start and working her way through most of her tasks.
By breaking tasks down and starting small,
Beth now has much less to do the next day and can go to bed feeling less overwhelmed.